<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INFRASTRUCTURE as CODE on Mussell Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/infrastructure-as-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INFRASTRUCTURE as CODE on Mussell Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2000 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/infrastructure-as-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure Automation with Ansible: Configuration Management at Scale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/ansible-infrastructure-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/ansible-infrastructure-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project demonstrates the design and implementation of scalable infrastructure automation using Ansible for configuration management across multi-environment deployments. The implementation follows infrastructure-as-code principles, enabling consistent, repeatable infrastructure provisioning and configuration management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Automated infrastructure provisioning across development, staging, and production&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reusable Ansible roles for common infrastructure patterns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrated with cloud providers (AWS, Azure) for dynamic inventory management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reduced manual configuration time by 85%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Achieved consistent infrastructure state across all environments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;business-context&#34;&gt;Business Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern infrastructure requires consistent configuration management across multiple environments. Manual configuration leads to drift, inconsistencies, and increased operational overhead. This project addresses the need for automated, repeatable infrastructure configuration that scales with organizational growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
