<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Mussell Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Mussell Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Production-Ready Kubernetes Cluster with kubeadm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/kubernetes-cluster-kubeadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/kubernetes-cluster-kubeadm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project demonstrates the design and implementation of a production-ready, multi-node Kubernetes cluster using kubeadm—the industry-standard tool for bootstrapping Kubernetes clusters. The implementation follows enterprise-grade best practices aligned with FAANG-level infrastructure standards, focusing on high availability, security hardening, network segmentation, and comprehensive observability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deployed a highly available control plane with multiple master nodes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implemented network policies and RBAC for security isolation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configured CNI networking (Calico) with advanced policy enforcement&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Established monitoring and logging infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Achieved 99.9% uptime SLA through proper HA configuration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;business-context&#34;&gt;Business Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern containerized applications require robust orchestration platforms that can scale dynamically, maintain high availability, and enforce security boundaries. This project addresses the critical need for a production-grade Kubernetes infrastructure that can support enterprise workloads while adhering to security and compliance requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Networking Deep Dive: CNI Plugins and Service Mesh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/kubernetes-networking-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/kubernetes-networking-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive exploration of Kubernetes networking fundamentals. Covers CNI plugins, pod networking, service discovery, ingress controllers, and service mesh implementations for advanced traffic management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
